AIRUL AIMAN BIN AIRIL AZHAR

Bachelor's Degree in Engineering Computer with Honors

Github: Portfolio project via Bootstrap

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/airul-aiman-b7b0241bb/

<u>Malaysia</u>

Phone. No: 011-11918632

Email: airulaimanairilazhar@gmail.com

Professional Profile

I am a Computer Engineering student at University Malaysia Perlis currently pursuing my Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering With Honors intake 2020/2021, I have a passion when it comes to Information Technology Fields and has been self-learning since a young age. I have developed several Projects when I was studying such as a database record system using HTML, CSS, and MYSQL. This is just an example of the projects that I have learned throughout the years.

Core Skills

- Creativity
- Problem-solving
- Flexibility
- Troubleshooting
- Desktop support
- IT Support
- User Administration

Career Summary

Education:

Politeknik Merlimau Melaka

Diploma Engineering Electrical Computer

Jun 2016 - April 2019

- I have been responsible for building my Project where I create both apps and software
 for security parents to monitor their children at all times, I have also experience making
 my website using HTML and CSS to create a data keying where I was participating in
 my internship for 6 months and also been given opportunity to teach one of the
 classes there at Kolej Komuniti Tanjung piai
- First Place in the Final Year Project Contest category for Faculty and the Whole

department

 Lead My Group to run an event on DTK days where students celebrate faculty achievements

University Perlis Malaysia

Bachelor of Engineering Computer(Hons)

2020 - 2024

CGPA 2.94 Last semester

Working Experience:

Kolej Komuniti Tanjung Piai

Internship Desktop Support

Dec 2018 - April 2019

- Responsible for technical solving for lecture and secretary computer equipment
- Networking troubleshooting for College Wan/Lan setup and troubleshooting
- Installing software and troubleshooting extensive software problems and errors
- Provide support on several class lectures while the lecturer is on duty for another responsibility
- Giving Lectures on operating system fundamentals for 6 months and Html and CSS classes for students.
- Participate in developing website data keying for student records and information database using xampp, HTML, and CSS
- Support on server management for the college website and database.

Student Faculty Company in Politeknik

Computers and laptop repairs

Jun 2016 - April 2019

- Repair student Computer and laptops required for their semester subject in engineering faculty
- Installing software for the students based on request
- Responsible for networking cabling for computer labs and engineering electrical lab equipment
- Slight on-site CCTV installation observation to provide understanding.

Mega Intech Computer

Computer salesman and repair

July 2019 – August 2020

- Sales clerk on site
- Repairing customer computer responsible for formatting, backup, and installing the

necessary software

• In-depth on Repairing computer

University Malaysia Perlis

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering with (Honors) 2020 – 2024

Currently Studying and now my Third Year 6th Semester for 2023.

Key Responsibility:

- Implementing Computer technology solutions across the college users
- Testing software and applications rigorously, identifying issues, and debugging
- Installation, configuration, and upgrading of Software key and hardware
- Creation and maintenance of user guides for systems
- Analysing computer and laptop performance and identifying opportunities to improve their efficiency
- Diagnosing hardware and software issues presented by lectures and colleague

Key Achievements:

- Improved user experience by implementing recommendations on new hardware
- Identified and removed security and performance flaws in legacy systems, resulting in cost-saving for the business.

Skills:

Software

- Microsoft office
- Excel
- Microsoft Windows
- Powerpoint

Hardware

- Desktops
- Laptop
- Printers

Language

- English
- Bahasa Melayu

Award

- First place in both categories on my course and faculty in Final Year Project creating an application named The Eyes
- First place in group Project on making an app using C coding
- Leader responsible for maintaining events at Politeknik Merlimau for our DTK day